[
 {
   "No": 1,
   "Quiz question": "What does the word dinosaur mean in Greek?",
   "Answer": "Fearful lizard"
 },
 {
   "No": 2,
   "Quiz question": "Mention the dinosaur whose name means “lizard under a roof”",
   "Answer": "Stegosaurus"
 },
 {
   "No": 3,
   "Quiz question": "Mention the name of the dinosaur, which translates as “well protected head”",
   "Answer": "Euoplocephalus"
 },
 {
   "No": 4,
   "Quiz question": "Mention the name of the dinosaur, which means “lizard-tyrant”:",
   "Answer": "Tyrannosaurus"
 },
 {
   "No": 5,
   "Quiz question": "Trilobites are the closest “relatives” of which fish?",
   "Answer": "Crayfish"
 },
 {
   "No": 6,
   "Quiz question": "Stegocephalus is a representative of which kind of animal?",
   "Answer": "Amphibians"
 },
 {
   "No": 7,
   "Quiz question": "Which period is characterized by thick forests formed by giant ferns, puzzlegrass and clubmoss?",
   "Answer": "Carboniferous period"
 },
 {
   "No": 8,
   "Quiz question": "When did dinosaurs become extinct?",
   "Answer": "Approximately 65 million years ago"
 },
 {
   "No": 9,
   "Quiz question": "Birds and mammals evolved from which group of animals?",
   "Answer": "Reptiles"
 },
 {
   "No": 10,
   "Quiz question": "The plesiosaurus was an ancient reptile. What ability did it have?",
   "Answer": "Ability to swim"
 },
 {
   "No": 11,
   "Quiz question": "Mention the dinosaur whose name translates as “double beamed”",
   "Answer": "Diplodocus"
 },
 {
   "No": 12,
   "Quiz question": "Mention the dinosaur whose name is translated as “elegant jaw”",
   "Answer": "Compsognathus"
 },
 {
   "No": 13,
   "Quiz question": "Mention the dinosaur whose name means “deep chest lizard”",
   "Answer": "Brachiosaurus"
 },
 {
   "No": 14,
   "Quiz question": "The name of which dinosaur means “triple horned”?",
   "Answer": "Triceratops"
 },
 {
   "No": 15,
   "Quiz question": "When did the life of earth begin according to scientists?",
   "Answer": "Approximately 3.5 billion years ago"
 },
 {
   "No": 16,
   "Quiz question": "Dinichtys is a representative of which group of animals?",
   "Answer": "Fish"
 },
 {
   "No": 17,
   "Quiz question": "When did ancient reptiles begin to thrive?",
   "Answer": "Approximately 350,000 years ago"
 },
 {
   "No": 18,
   "Quiz question": "During which period did dinosaurs thrive?",
   "Answer": "Jurassic period"
 },
 {
   "No": 19,
   "Quiz question": "Pterosaurus was an ancient reptile. Which ability did it have?",
   "Answer": "Ability to fly"
 },
 {
   "No": 20,
   "Quiz question": "Ichtiosaurus was an ancient reptile. Which ability did it have?",
   "Answer": "Ability to swim"
 },
 {
   "No": 21,
   "Quiz question": "During which era did dinosaurs dominate the world?",
   "Answer": "Mesozoic era"
 },
 {
   "No": 22,
   "Quiz question": "For how many years did dinosaurs dominate the Earth?",
   "Answer": "160 million years"
 },
 {
   "No": 23,
   "Quiz question": "Which natural phenomenon caused an evolutionary explosion among reptiles?",
   "Answer": "Global warming"
 },
 {
   "No": 24,
   "Quiz question": "What is called the most ancient species of dinosaurs known to man?",
   "Answer": "Staurikosaurus"
 },
 {
   "No": 25,
   "Quiz question": "Which dinosaur was larger than the tyrannosaurus?",
   "Answer": "Spinosaurus"
 },
 {
   "No": 26,
   "Quiz question": "Which dinosaurs did have feathers?",
   "Answer": "Caudipteryx"
 },
 {
   "No": 27,
   "Quiz question": "The first dinosaur eggs were discovered in 1859. Which dinosaur did they belong to?",
   "Answer": "Hypselosaurus"
 },
 {
   "No": 28,
   "Quiz question": "Whic dinosaur was discovered in the Antarctic?",
   "Answer": "Ankylosaurus"
 },
 {
   "No": 29,
   "Quiz question": "To which dinosaur does the largest skull belong?",
   "Answer": "Torosaurus"
 }
]